麦琪:杰森,现在切熏肉,有点早吧?
Maggie: Jason, isn't it a little early to start the bacon?
杰森:呵!不早,
Jason: He! Not in this family.
在这个家里,
The only way I can get a slice is to cook it early.
我像吃块肉的唯一办法就是早点煮,越早越好.
The earlier the better.
麦琪:这太好笑了.
Maggie: That's ridiculous.
杰森:不可笑,麦琪,那是自卫.
Jason: It's not ridiculous Maggie. It's self-defense.
(电话铃声)
(Phone rings)
杰森:很顺利,麦琪,非常顺利.你好,
Jason: Smooth Maggie, very smooth. Hello, ah ha. Who's this?
啊哈,你是谁?不可能,我没有一个可爱的岳父.
That's impossible, I don't have a favorite father in law.
麦琪:是爸爸?
Maggie: It's daddy?
杰森:爱德,你好吗?多近?
Jason: Ed, how are you? How close?
麦琪:他们近了?
Maggie: They're close?
杰森:等一下.什么时候?
Jason: Stopping by. When?
麦琪:他们来这儿?
Maggie: They're coming here?
杰森:嘘!是的,是的,不.欢迎你,爱德,换个环境很好.
Jason: Shh! Yeah. Yeah, no. That's nice of you to call first Ed. For a change.
麦琪:什么时候?
Maggie: When?
杰森:你们什么时候到呢?
Jason: So, when can we expect you?
(汽车喇叭声)
(Car horn)
杰森:对不起,我听不见说什么,一群疯子在这儿摁喇叭.
Jason: Sorry, I can't hear you. Some lunatics honking his horn here.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
杰森:好,你和你父亲说话吧,我去看一下是迈克的哪位朋友.
Jason: Ok, you talk to your father, while I go yell at one of Mike's friends.
麦琪:你好,爸爸,你们笑什么?
Maggie: Hi daddy. Why are you laughing?
爱德:哈哈哈!
Ed: Ha ha ha!
杰森:嘿,有人想进来睡觉.
Jason: Hey, people are trying to sleep in...
爱德:汽车电话很棒吧?
Ed: Aren't car phones wonderful?
麦琪:哦,他们在这儿,汽车电话真不错.爸爸,妈妈,你们穿越了整个国家,真令我吃惊.
Maggie: Oh, they're here. Aren't car phones wonderful? Daddy, mum. The cross country travelers. What
a wonderful surprise
爱德:嘿,你还是没什么手劲.
Ed: Hey, you still don't have much of a grip do you?
杰森:很高兴见到你,爱德.
Jason: Good to see you too Ed.
麦琪:你们那辆温尼贝戈车呢?
Maggie: What happened to the Winnebago?
外婆:你爸爸用那车换了这辆,在辛辛纳提和一个男妓换的.
Grandma: You father swapped it for this with some pimp in Cincinnati.
麦琪:妈妈,你怎么会知道是他是男妓呢?
Maggie: Mum, how do you know what a pimp looks like?
外婆:我听过格拉迪斯骑士和男妓的每一首歌曲.
Grandma: I know every song recorded by Gladys Knight and the Pimps.
现在让我见见我的小外孙女吧.
Now take me to meet my new granddaughter.
杰森:这就是来这儿的车.
Jason: This is some car you got here.
爱德:我感觉很不错,对于人的态度.如果你懂我意思的话.
Ed: I feel it's good for a fellows, uh, attitude. If you get my drift.
杰森:是的,你们这些天一直在路上吗?
Jason: Yeah, well does that mean that your days on the road are over?
爱德:我们买了一套退休公寓,我想知道整天坐着,
Ed: We're going to give retirement condo living a try.
啥也不做是啥滋味,
I want to know what it feels like to sit around and do nothing all day
看起来你也同意.我闻到的是熏肉的味道吗?
long. It sure seems to agree with you. Is that bacon I'm smelling now?
杰森:不是.
Jason: No.
爱德:肯定是的.等我把行李取出来,
Ed: It's got to be. Wait till I get my tote bag.
你知道我最爱吃熏肉了.
You know me and bacon.
杰森:是的,我知道.我们屋里见.
Jason: Yes I do. I'll see you inside.
迈克:嘿,外公.你太了不起了.
Mike: Hey grandpa. Ah you were great.
爱德:迈克.
Ed: Michael.
迈克:嘿,你们好吗?
Mike: Hey, how you doing?
爱德:我很好.你们喜欢我的车吗?
Ed: Sure I was great. How do you like my wheels?
迈克:啊,这车比你说得还棒.
Mike: Ah, this thing is hotter than you said.
爱德:靓车佩帅仔.
Ed: Hot car for a hot guy.
迈克:哦.
Mike: yeah.
爱德:听着,迈克,你准备好了吗?
Ed: Listen Michael, is everything all set up?
迈克:好了,我所有一切都安排好了.
Mike: Yeah. I've taken care of the whole shebang.
爱德:你妈不会怀疑吧?
Ed: Your mother doesn't suspect anything?
迈克:不会.
Mike: No.
爱德:还有你爸呢?
Ed: And your dad?
迈克:爸爸还不知情.
Mike: Dad doesn't have a clue.
爱德:我知道,不过到如今他该惊讶了.
Ed: Well I know that, but is he on to the surprise by now?
本:外公,我什么时候可以坐你车?
Ben: Grandpa, when do I get a ride in your corvette?
爱德:哦,本,时间有的是.我们要在这至少待一个月.
Ed: Oh, we've got plenty of time for that Ben. We're going to be here for at least a month.
麦琪和杰森:什么?
Maggie and Jason: What?
爱德:波士顿的公寓,还没有妥当,所以我们在这之前只能在你们这儿借住一下了.
Ed: That condo in Boston, it's not going to be ready right away. So we were kind of hoping that we could bunk here with you until it is. Eh?
麦琪:哦,爸爸,那太好了,杰森?
Maggie: Oh daddy, that would be great. Jason?
杰森:太好了不是这么说.
Jason: Great isn't the word.
外婆:开萝尔,你看起来又苗条又性感,是什么让你决定减肥的?
Grandma: And Carol, you are looking so svelte and sexy. What made you decide to loose all that weight?
迈克:要是不减肥,我们只能扩建房子了.出界了,第四球了.
Mike: It was either that or we add onto the house. High outside. Ball four.
爱德:杰森,你能再给我一块熏肉吗?
Ed: Could you grab that other pound of bacon for me Jason?
杰森:那已经是第二块了,爱德.
Jason: That was the other pound of bacon Ed.
爱德:你们已经吃光了?
Ed: You guys have gone through both of them already?
杰森:要是你们提前一天打电话通知的话,我肯定会准备一头猪来招待你.
Jason: Well if you'd called and given me say a days notice in advance, I would have had a dead pig waiting for you.
爱德:为了提前感谢你们让我们在这儿借住,
Ed: You know, to say thank you in advance for letting us bunk in here
凯蒂和我想带你和杰森出去吃晚饭.
with you, Katie and I would like to take you and Jason out to dinner tonight.
麦琪:哦,爸爸,没必要.
Maggie: Oh, daddy, that won't be necessary.
杰森:麦琪,你爸爸要请我们吃饭.
Jason: Maggie, the man wants to buy us dinner.
爱德:我没有说请客,我只是说带你们出去吃.
Ed: I didn't say buy dinner, I said take you out to dinner.
麦琪:跟我来,妈妈.我们给克莉丝洗个澡,换上衣服.
Maggie: Come on mum. Let's get Chrissy bathed and dressed.
外婆:哦,她累了.
Grandma: Oh, she pooped.
本:外公,我可以洗你的新车吗?
Ben: Grandpa, can I wash your new car?
爱德:可以的,孩子.
Ed: Sure you can lad.
杰森:你也可以洗我的新车,孩子.
Jason: And you can wash my new car too lad.
本:好的.
Ben: Yeah right.
杰森:我想我最好去杂货店买些东西,
Jason: Well, I guess I better get down to the grocery store and stock up.
我们有客人要住一个月.
If we are going to have guests for a month.
爱德:你要喝些咖啡吗?
Ed: Would you pick up some of that decaf coffee for yourself?
你们看上去有点紧张.
You're beginning to look a little tense.
开萝尔:哦,外公,他发现了以后会很高兴的.
Carol: Oh Grandpa, he is going to be so excited when he finds out.
爱德:哦,是的,我们要办一个精彩的20周年聚会.
Ed: Oh, yeah, we are going to have a wonderful anniversary party.
开萝尔:我是说他们发现你们不住一个月.
Carol: I was talking about him finding out that you're not going to be
staying for a month.
本:他们什么时候出去吃晚餐?他们什么时候出去吃晚餐?
Ben: When are they going to leave for dinner? When are they going to leave for dinner?
迈克:嘿,别紧张,你会把自己弄湿的.
Mike: Hey relax or you are going to wet yourself.
开萝尔:嘘!
Carol: Shh!
爱德:嘿,再检查一遍,食品放好了吗?
Ed: Hey now just to double check, the food is on its way?
开萝尔:外公,相信我.成堆的食物成堆的人.
Carol: Grandpa, trust me. There's going to be tons of food, tons of people..
外婆:成堆的快乐.嘿,我说了个笑话.
Grandma: And tons of fun. Hey, I made a joke!
爱德:不,你没有凯蒂.好了,我们的人七点半之前不许来这.
Ed: Nah you didn't Kate. Ok, we're going to keep your folks away till about seven thirty.
迈克:太好了.
Mike: Perfect.
外婆:开萝尔,你要请个男朋友来参加聚会吗?
Grandma: Carol, did you invite a boyfriend to this party?
开萝尔:桑迪他还不是我的男朋友,不过我会让他来这儿的.
Carol: Well he's not exactly my boyfriend yet, but yes. Sandy will be here.
本:我的女朋友也来.
Ben: My girlfriends coming too.
爱德:哦,你现在就有女朋友了,本?
Ed: Oh, you got a girlfriend now do you Ben?
本:是的,也是相当认真的.
Ben: Yeah. It's pretty serious too.
她是我遇见的第一个不让我恶心的女孩.
She's the first girl I've ever met who doesn't make me puke.
外婆:很好,这很重要.
Grandma: Well, that's important.
爱德:迈克,你呢?你今晚有吗?
Ed: How about you Mikey? You got a hot one on for this evening?
迈克:哦,没有.我今晚是光棍.
Mike: Oh no. No I'm going stag tonight.
爱德:但是你通常是一个很有女人缘的人哪.
Ed: But you are usually such a ladies man.
外婆:爱德,别逼他.
Grandma: Eddie, don't push him.
如果他不喜欢女孩,就让他不喜欢吧.
If he doesn't like girls, he doesn't like girls.
麦琪:你想让我做什么,杰森?
Maggie: What do you want me to do Jason? Send my parents to the YMCA?
送我的父母去基督教青年会吗?青年会,我爱这歌.
YMCA! I love that song.
开萝尔:你记得让朱莉来照看克莉丝?
Carol: Did you remember to Julie about coming over to take care of Chrissy?
迈克:知道,我打了电话,朱莉准备好了.
Mike: Yeah. I called. Julie's all set.
开萝尔:好的.操办宴会的人一小时后到,第一批客人一个半小时后到.都安排好了.
Carol: Ok. The caterers get here in an hour. The first guests in an hour and a half. This is going to go like clockwork.
(门铃声)
(Door bell)
迈克:可能朱莉到了.
Mike: Probably Julie right now.
戴维:戴维 萨克斯,聚会筹办公司的,聚会开始吧!
Dave: Dave Sacks, Party Animal Party Rentals. Let's party!
开萝尔:你来早了.
Carol: You're early.
戴维:我没地方去.
Man: I had nowhere to go.
开萝尔:去厨房吧.
Carol: The kitchen's that way.
迈克:听着,你们没有把你们的车停在车道上吧?
Mike: Yeah well listen. You didn't park your van in our drive way did you?
因为这是一个想带来惊喜的聚会.
Because it's a surprise party.
戴维:他们没有给我车.
Man: They don't give me a van.
迈克:他准时吗?
Mike: Clockwork he?
开萝尔:哦,如果再出错的话,我就是个傻瓜?
Carol: Oh, so one mistake and I'm a bozo?
(门铃声)
(Door bell)
迈克:你开门吧,傻瓜.
Mike: Your turn bozo.
乌玛:你好,宝贝.
Urma: Hi hi hi! Hi sweetheart.
威利:你好,亲爱的.
Wally: Hi sweetie.
乌玛:迈克.哦.
Urma: And Mikey. Ooh!
威利:你好吗?
Wally: How are you?
开萝尔:奶奶,威利,你来早了.
Carol: Grandma, Wally, you're early.
威利:你奶奶想你可能需要帮忙,开萝尔.
Wally: Well your grandmother thought you might need some help Carol.
迈克:是的.你们有是整形外科医生的吗?
Mike: Yeah, she does. Any of you a plastic surgeon.
乌玛:迈克!你还是老样子,宝贝,所有事情都安排好了吗?
Urma: Mike! You never change. Honey, is everything all set?
开萝尔:奶奶,都安排好了.
Carol: Grandma, everything is going to go perfectly.
乌玛:你妈妈不怀疑吗?
Urma: And your mum doesn't suspect a thing.
开萝尔:不会.
Carol: No.
威利:你爸爸呢?
Wally: Your dad?
本:爸爸还不知情.
Ben: Dad doesn't have a clue.
威利:我知道,但是他快来了吧?
Wally: I know, but is he on to the party?
开萝尔:嘘嘘!是他们,是他们!
Carol: Shh! Shh! It's them! It's them!
所有人:结婚20周年快乐!
Everyone: Happy Anniversary!
开萝尔:只有桑迪.
Carol: Only Sandy.
桑迪:只有桑迪?
Sandy: Only Sandy?
开萝尔:我意思是说只有桑迪,我只深爱着他.
Carol: I meant the one and only Sandy, who I care about deeply.
乌玛:他们怎么还没来?现在七点四十五了.
Urma: Shouldn't they be here? Its seven forty five.
开萝尔:等等,他们真的来了.所有人都躲起来.
Carol: Wait, it's really them this time. Everyone hide.
所有人:结婚20周年快乐!
Everyone: Happy Anniversary!
拉里:嘿嘿.笑起来!
Larry: Hey hey! Cheer up! Larry is here. So let the games begin.
拉里在这儿,聚会开始了,幸福20周年的夫妻呢?
So where's the happy twentieth anniversary couple?
开萝尔:他们还没来,你是?
Carol: They're not here yet, and you are?
拉里:拉里表弟,你肯定是查理了.
Larry: Cousin Larry. And you have got to be Charlie.
开萝尔:不是,是开萝尔!
Carol: No, Carol.
拉里:开萝尔,这是一个男女通用的名字.
Larry: Close, I knew it was a bisexual name.
牧师:太糟糕了,杰森,你头发少多了,不过你看上去很好.
Minister: Too bad about you losing the hair Jason. But damn it, you look good.
戴维:谢谢你,牧师,该死的,我感觉很好.
Dave: Well thanks padre. Damn it I feel good.
迈克:怎么来的大多数人我们都不认识?
Mike: How come we don't know most of these people?
开萝尔:怪我,我是根据妈妈圣诞卡上的名单发的邀请.
Carol: Beats me. I used mums Christmas card list for the invitations.
朱莉:迈克,拉里来这儿不到一分钟,
Julie: Mike, that Larry creatures been here less than a minute,
他已经掐我两次了.
and he's already pinched me twice.
迈克:嘿,我没法责怪他.
Mike: Hey, I can't say I blame him.
朱莉:迈克.
Julie: Mike please.
迈克:别冲着我发火,又不是我干的.
Mike: Don't snap at me. I didn't do it.
朱莉:我干嘛要和你说呢?你都找不到一个舞伴.
Julie: What am I talking to you for? You couldn't even get a date.
所有人:结婚20周年快乐!哦.
Everyone: Happy Anniversary! Oh.
迈克:外公好,妈妈和爸爸在吗?
Mike: Hey grandpa, is mum and dad here?
爱德:别急.我赢了他一英里.
Ed: Relax. I beat him by a mile.
他应该弄个好刹车,"我每一样都赢了".
He should have a bumper sticker "I break for everything".
乌玛:爱德,哈哈.
Urma: Eddie! Ha ha.
爱德:乌玛!
Ed: Urma!
乌玛:你们怎么样,你这个老平足?
Urma: How have you been, you old flat foot?
爱德:很好.你们怎么样,尊贵的夫人?
Ed: Great. How have you been you gorgeous dame?
乌玛:非常好,凯蒂.
Urma: Wonderful. Kate.
外婆:乌玛.
Grandma: Urma.
乌玛:爱德和凯蒂,我给你们两个介绍我特别的伙伴,
Urma: I want you two to meet my special fellow.
这是威利?欧维玛尔,我的未婚夫.
Ed and Kate, this is Wally Overmyer, my fiancé.
威利:凯蒂,你好,爱德.
Wally: Kate. Hello Ed.
爱德:你就是麦琪说过的那个兵吧.
Ed: You must be that soldier boy Maggie told us about.
乌玛:上尉,美国陆军,已经退伍了.
Urma: Captain. US Army. Retired.
爱德:哦,一位军官.
Ed: Oh. An officer. I was in the real Army myself.
我自己也在陆军待过.你在朝鲜服过役吗?
You ever serve any time in Korea.
威利:是的,我去了两次.你呢?
Wally: Yes, I've been there twice. You?
爱德:哦,
Ed: Oh, you bet. Ya, military police.
我是宪兵.美国宪兵经常抓去酒吧喝酒的士兵,
Us MP's used to wipe up the bars with you guys pretty regular.
我可能抓过你一两次.
I bet I may have even slung you over my jeep once or twice.
威利:哦,我不这样认为,
Wally: Oh, I don't think so Ed.
爱德.我遇见的唯一一位宪兵是个大嗓门的小丑.
The only MP's I ever met were loud mouth clowns.
本:嘿,大家好.爸妈到了前门走廊了.
Ben: Hey everybody. Mum and dad are coming up the front porch.
迈克:嘿,看好了.你确信是他们,不是另一位客人吗?
Mike: Hey look. Are you sure it's them and not just another guest?
拉里:嘿,有哪个粗鲁的家伙会这么晚来参加这个惊喜聚会呢?哈,哈,哈.
Larry: Hey. What kind of rude jerk would show up late to a surprise party? Ha ha ha.
杰森:你爸爸应该弄一个好刹车,
Jason: Your father should have a bumper sticker that says "I don't break
写着"我每一样都属了".
for anything".
麦琪:哦,杰森,至少那顿饭很不错.
Maggie: Oh Jason, at least the meal was nice.
杰森:是的,我付的钱.
Jason: Sure it was. I paid for it.
麦琪:我以为我爸爸会拿账单的.
Maggie: I thought my dad was going to pick up the check.
杰森:哦,他拿了,然后他给了我.
Jason: Oh he did. Then he handed it to me.
哦,过来,宝贝,
Oh now come on honey, be honest.
说实话.要是我这边的亲戚突然不通知就来了,你会怎么样?
How would you feel if suddenly my side of the family showed up unannounced?
麦琪:嗯.
Maggie: Ugh!
杰森:确实是.
Jason: Exactly.
所有人:结婚20周年快乐!
Everyone: Happy Anniversary!
杰森:妈妈!这真是太棒了,但是我们的纪念日还有两个星期呢.
Jason: Mum! Well this is great but, our anniversary isn't for two weeks.
麦琪:三个星期.
Maggie: Three weeks.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Exactly.
乌玛:我们知道,不过这样才会让你们吃惊.
Urma: We know. That's what was so clever about my surprise party.
这是我的主意.
If I do say so myself.
外婆:你的主意!
Grandma: Your idea!
拉里:别动!我们拍张照片吧.
Larry: Hold it! Let's get a picture. I don't have a camera.
我没有照相机.嘿,非得要我一手操办吗?
Hey do I have to do everything?
爱德:杰森,杰森,
Ed: Jason. Jason, you should have seen the way your eyes bugged out when
当我告诉你我们要住一个月的时候,你的眼珠都快掉下来了.
I told you we were bunking in for a month.
杰森:你是说你们不是?
Jason: So you mean you're not?
爱德:哦,当然不是,那只是惊喜的一部分.
Ed: Oh heck no. That was just part of the surprise scam.
杰森:哈,哈,哈,谢谢你,谢谢你,谢谢你,谢谢你.
Jason: Ha ha ha. Thank you. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
麦琪:你们这些孩子也参与了?
Maggie: Now were you kids in on this?
开萝尔:是的,我发了请帖.
Carol: I sure was. I sent the invitations.
迈克:现在我知道你为什么只寄给这些人圣诞卡了.
Mike: Now I know why you only send these people Christmas cards.
开萝尔:是的,每个人.先吃点,然后妈妈爸爸将重新宣读20年前的誓言.
Carol: Ok everybody. After some more mingling and eating, mum and dad will re-pledge the troth the pledged almost twenty years ago.
所有人:好!(喝彩声)
Everybody: Yeah! (Applause)
开萝尔:最好的一个消息是我找到了尊敬的迈克格雷戈牧师,就是他主持了当年的婚礼.
Carol: And, and the best news of all is that I was able to find the Reverend Chuck McGregor, the minister who performed the original ceremony.
所有人:好!(喝彩声)
Everybody: Yeah! (Applause)
牧师:哦.如果你们没有玛格丽塔酒了,我有可拉达冰酒.
Minister: Oh hi. If you are out of Margarita mix, I'll have a Pina Colada.
朱莉:首先,我不叫宝贝.
Julie: First, my name's not babe.
第二,我照看克莉丝,我不是保姆.
Second, I take care of Chrissy, I'm not the help.
而且,我不是那种法国少女.
And no I do not own one of those out of sight French maid outfits.
拉里:嘿,我只是想和你谈一谈,宝贝.别激动!
Larry: Hey, I was just trying to make a little small talk here babe. Chill out!
迈克:有问题吗,拉里?
Mike: Uh, is there a problem Larry?
拉里:不.没问题.嘿,
Larry: No, no problem. Hey look Mikey.
看,迈克.我知道你今晚没有女伴.
I couldn't help noticing that you are a stag at this deal. Ha ha ha.
哈,哈,
Me too. So I'm warning you,
哈,我也是.我得提醒你,
I've already staked my claim on blondie over there.
这个金发姑娘你别和我争.哦,她一直都关注着我.
Ooh hoo, she's got her eyes on the prize.
迈克:我们说的是朱莉?
Mike: Ah, are we talking about Julie?
拉里:朱莉.嘿,谢谢,她要我,我想这是我的弱点.
Larry: Julie. Hey thanks, she wants me. I think it's my vulnerability.
迈克:听着,拉里.我认为朱莉不会对你感兴趣.
Mike: Yeah well listen. Larry. I don't think Julie would be interested in you.
拉里:好了!
Larry: Yeah right!
迈克:不,
Mike: No I'm serious.
我很认真.我真不知道是否应该告诉你,
I mean I don't know if I should tell you this,
她曾经是个男人.
but she used to be a guy.
拉里:男人!
Larry: A guy?
迈克:是的.
Mike: Yeah.
拉里:去你的.
Larry: Get out of town.
迈克:不,
Mike: No, no I'm serious.
我是认真的.
Before the operation, we used to be fraternity brothers.
在手术之前,我们曾经是一对好兄弟,
Hey aren't you glad I told you before you went and made a fool out of
你难道不乐意我在你出洋相之前告诉你真相吗?
yourself?
拉里:不,伙计.嘿,朱莉,尼克斯他们怎么样了?
Larry: Not now kid. Hey Julie. How about them Nicks?
乌玛:凯蒂,我刚才只是说你可能错了.
Urma: Kate, I was just saying that perhaps you were mistaken.
外婆:错了!乌玛,亲爱的,我相信这个,就像我相信我头发的颜色.
Grandma: Mistaken! Urma dear, I'm as sure of this as I am my own hair colour.
乌玛:我也相信,就像我相信我的腰围抵得上两个人.
Urma: Well I'm as sure of this as I am a size two.
外婆和乌玛:麦琪!麦琪!
Grandma and Urma: Maggie! Maggie!
乌玛:过来,亲爱的.
Urma: Come here dear.
麦琪:妈妈,乌玛,那是什么?
Maggie: Mum, Urma, what is it?
外婆:乌玛有个错误的看法,她认为克莉丝看起来像他们家里的人.
Grandma: Urma has this misguided notion that Chrissy looks like her side of the family.
乌玛:那没错,凯蒂.麦琪,
Urma: It is not a misguided notion Kate.
你同意我,是吧,麦琪?
Maggie you agreed with me, didn't you Maggie?
外婆:她没这么说,告诉她,亲爱的.
Grandma: That's not what she told me. Tell her dear.
乌玛:不是的?
Urma: It isn't?
麦琪:你穿的衣服真漂亮.
Maggie: Did I mention what a great dress that is?
外婆和乌玛:哦,谢谢你.
Grandma and Urma: Oh thank you.
本:你站在哪一边呢,爸爸?
Ben: So, who are you rooting for dad?
杰森:让我看看.爱德是我的岳父,
Jason: Well, let's see now. Ed is my father in law.
威利很快就要成为我的继父.所以……
Wally's going to be my step father soon. So, uh...
本女友:我想他们都快受不了了.
Ben's Girlfriend: I think they are both going to bust a gut.
杰森:我同意.
Jason: I could live with that.
威利:我赢了!
Wally: Got ya!
爱德:你没有赢.你耍赖,
Ed: You didn't get me. You cheated.
你的肘部已经离开这该死的桌子一尺高了.
Your elbow was a foot off the stinking table.
威利:就是霍迪尼.
Wally: The Houdini it was.
爱德:杰森,你看见了,告诉他.
Ed: Jason, Jay, you saw this. Tell him.
杰森:不,我在说话
Jason: No I was talking to the...
威利:告诉他,他就知道说大话.
Wally: Tell him he's full of malarkey.
桑迪:很棒的聚会.
Sandy: Nifty party.
开萝尔:你说这些只是因为我的家人都是一群疯子,你是出于礼貌,
Carol: Are you just saying that because my family are lunatics and you're
你就不能坦诚一点吗?
too polite to be honest?
桑迪:嗯.
Sandy: Yeh. Uh hu.
朱莉:不,我不想讨论我的手术.
Julie: No. I do not want to discuss my operation.
拉里:好好.你不想我看你的刀疤.
Larry: Ok. ok. Gee. It's not like I ask you to show me your scare or something.
本:这是诺拉,她是我的女朋友.
Ben: This is Nora. She's my girlfriend.
本女友:呃!
Ben's Girlfriend: Uh hu!
本:女伴.
Ben: Date.
本女友:呃!
Ben's Girlfriend: Hu hu!
本:宝贝.
Ben: Honey.
本女友:呃!
Ben's Girlfriend: Hu hu.
本:你到底是什么?
Ben: Well what the heck are you anyway?
牧师:孩子.不能不找个女伴吗?我也没有.
Minister: So kid. Couldn't snag a date for this hu? Me neither.
迈克:行啊,我也没有女伴,
Mike: No I could not find a date for this, alright.
好了.你想让我做什么?
What do you want me to do? Take an add out in the New York Times?
在上登广告?我们为什么不雇一个飞机乘客呢?
I got it, why don't we just hire a sky rider?
牧师:我忘了那个金发女郎.她以前是个男孩.
Minister: I'd forget about that blonde over there. She used to be a guy.
戴维:是你结婚纪念日吧?
Dave: Are you the anniversary couple?
杰森:是我.
Jason: Fraid so.
戴维:那么我想你得到了这个.专业信用卡,不是个人支票,恭喜你.
Dave: Then I guess you get this. Major credit cards. No personal checks. My mozeltov, etc etc.
本女友:不,我不想接受你的道歉.这真的很为难.你怎么能那样做?
Ben's Girlfriend: No. I'm not going to accept your apology. This is really embarrassing. How could you even do that?
开萝尔:我想提醒你们这些讨厌的家伙,我们都是一家人,
Carol: I would like to remind all you stinking people,
我们彼此相亲相爱,包括拉里.
that we are a family and we love each other. Even Larry.
拉里:谢谢你,查理.
Larry: Thank you Charlie.
开萝尔:请安静,大约20年前,我的外公爱德向这两位新人敬酒,从此他们开始了共同的生活.所以,外公,你愿意再敬一次酒吗?
Carol: Now, almost twenty years ago, my Grandpa Ed toasted two newly weds, as they began their life together. So grandpa, would you please lead us in another toast?
爱德:听着,听着,我并不擅长敬酒,不过,好的,我来敬.现在,我首先得承认我不看好这场婚姻能够维持下去.我曾经用一个星期的薪水打赌,麦琪加给杰森会是一场悲剧.
Ed: Look, look. I am not very good at this, but, well, well, here goes. Now, I'll be the first to admit that I didn't think this marriage was going to work in the first place. I would have bet a weeks pay that Maggie's marriage to Jason was going to end in disaster.
威利:你别开玩笑,你真得不擅长.
Wally: You weren't kidding. You're not very good at this.
爱德:我是说,当我们和一大群讨厌的家伙站在这,
Ed: What I'm saying is,
吃着糟糕的食物,
while we are mainly here with a lot of obnoxious people,
喝着廉价的酒,我们至少得假装我们过得很开心.
eating bad food and drinking cheap booze,
这次敬酒,
couldn't we at least pretend that we were having a good time?
是给麦琪和杰森的,谁知道呢?
Here's a toast, to Maggie and Jason. Who knew?
所有人:(喝彩声)
Everyone: (applause)
本:爸爸妈妈去哪儿了?
Ben: Where did mum and dad go?
麦琪:哦,杰森,你知道他们这样争吵,让我想起什么了吗?
Maggie: Oh Jason, you know what all that fighting in there reminds me of?
杰森:我们的婚礼.不过他们办了这次聚会,这让我们很惊喜.
Jason: Our wedding reception. Still it was real nice of the kids and our folks to surprise us with this party.
麦琪:哦,是的.
Maggie: Oh it sure was.
杰森:20年了.
Jason: Twenty years.
麦琪:是的.发生了太多变化.
Maggie: Yeah. So much has changed.
杰森:哦,我们曾经偷偷溜到他们的车库里约会,
Jason: Oh yeah. Yeah we used to have to sneak out behind their garage
现在我们只能溜到自己的车库里了.
to make out. Now we have to sneak out behind our own garage.
麦琪:哦,杰森,
Maggie: Oh Jason, I think that's the most romantic thing you've ever said
我想这是你对我说过的最浪漫的话.
to me.
杰森:我知道.
Jason: I know.
戴维:点心已经准备好了.
Dave: Dessert is served.
本:馅饼!我可以给你来一块吗?
Ben: Pie! Can I get you a slice?
本女友:当然,谢谢本.也许一小块就够了.
Ben's Girlfriend: Sure. Thanks Benjamin. Maybe just a small one.
本:是的,亲爱的.
Ben: Yes dear.
爱德:我帮你拿,乌玛.
Ed: Let me help you get that Urma.
威利:我来拿,爱德.
Wally: I'll handle that Ed.
外婆:爱德,威利可以做.
Grandma: Eddie, Wally can handle it.
爱德:我说我来做.
Ed: I said I would get it.
威利:爱德,我说我做.
Wally: Ed, I said I'd handle this.
(蛋糕扔到了凯蒂的脸上)
(Cake goes in Kate's face)
乌玛:凯蒂!
Urma: Kate!
外婆:你觉得这很有趣?
Grandma: You think that's funny?
乌玛:当然不是.(凯蒂把蛋糕扔在了乌玛的脸上)
Urma: Of course I don't. (Kate throws cake in Urma's face)
迈克:外婆!
Mike: Grandma!
威利:你认为这很有趣?(蛋糕扔在了拉里的脸上)
Wally: You think that's funny? (Cake goes in Larry's face)
朱莉:迈克,迈克,克莉丝在睡觉.(蛋糕扔在了朱莉的脸上)
Julie: Mike, mike. Chrissy's asleep. (Cake goes in Julie's face)
拉里:喔!对不起,伙计们.
Larry: Woops! Sorry buddy.
本:这是你的馅饼.(蛋糕扔在了本女朋友的脸上)(本把他的脸埋在了馅饼里)
Ben: Here's your pie. (Cake goes in Ben's girlfriend's face) (Ben puts his face in his pie)
(食物大战开始)
(Food fight begins)
麦琪:那儿怎么了?
Maggie: What the heck is going on in there?
杰森:哦,过来,
Jason: Oh come on honey. It's a room full of our relatives.
宝贝.房间里都是我们的亲戚,能有什么事呢?
What could be going on?
麦琪:哦,我不想知道.
Maggie: Oh I don't want to know.
杰森:那些是什么?
Jason: What are those?
麦琪:爸爸的钥匙.
Maggie: Daddy's keys.
杰森:哦,是的!
Jason: Oh yeah!
麦琪:你说我们要私奔吗?
Maggie: What do you say we elope?
杰森:只要我能开车,
Jason: As long as I can drive.
我听说这些车可以影响一个人的态度.
I hear these cars do great things for a guy's attitude.
麦琪:哦!
Maggie: Ooh!
杰森:哦,是的.
Jason: Ooh yeah.
迈克:(读朱莉门上的纸条:如果你是小偷,那你肯定走错了;如果你是迈克,我去买比萨饼了.)至少我们不会挨饿.(进来,待在屋里,钥匙在爱迪生先生的发明里.)爱迪生!这儿没电话啊.啊,爱迪生.(电视上的纸条:不是电视,我们在学习)我知道了,宝贝,听着,在你说话之前我想说,我今晚本来可以有一个女伴的.胆识我知道,你是最好的,我们得对我们的关系保密.我们一起来面对,你也可以有一个男伴.嘿,你吻了一个漂亮小伙.
朱莉:闭嘴,迈克.
00:21:46,100
Mike: (reading a note on Julie's door: If you are a burglar, boy have you got the wrong apartment. If it's you Mike, I ran out to get pizza.) Well at least we won't starve. (So come on in and make yourself at home. The key is inside Mr. Edison's invention.) Edison! There's no phone around here. Ah that Edison. (Note on the TV says: No TV. We are studying) I knew that. Oh honey, listen, now before you even say a word, I just want to say, I could have really used a date tonight. But I know, you're right. We have to keep our relationship a secret. Let's face it; you could have used a date too. Hey, you kiss pretty good for a guy. Julie: Shut up Mike.